<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>education | Qiushi Yan</title>
    <link>/tags/education/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>education</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Qiushi Yan © 2019</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>education</title>
      <link>/tags/education/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Of Certificate</title>
      <link>/post/of-certificate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/of-certificate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the ever-growing expansion of higher education, today’s world has seen college graduates growing in larger numbers, leading to fierce competition in the talent market, where a subtle craze for various of certificates is on the rise and here to stay. Students took several weeks or months cramming for an examination to get one certificate for qualification, and they aimed at another certificate afterwards, irrespective of what previous cramming has brought him or future learning routes on the subject concerned. What’s more, various training institutions sprouting up these days are also in a ferment. They go out their way to inculcate in the minds of patrons the importance of those certificates. Implanted the beliefs, many are under the illusion that certificates are panacea and selling points for their resume, that it would open up hidden opportunities. These convictions, however inappropriate, add to the mania.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does a cupboard bedecked with certificates necessarily means competence? The answer is a qualified yes. The ultimate value of any accomplishment, including gaining certificates, depends on the what kind of capability to which it attests and what it will bring to us aside from physical evidence of any sort. Work that are too ambiguous to demonstrate certain abilities are rarely helpful, thus is not worth questing. And Work that revolves around rote learning without inspiring, is another slippery slope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certificates offered nowadays are multifarious. Take university students for example, one has a wide selection among CET 4 and CET 6 certificates, computer certificate, lawyer certificate, tour guide certificate, certified public accountant, certified tax accountant etc. And it is because this variety and inclusiveness, on the part of all these certificates, that make the majority of them don’t lend themselves to an adequate testament to the specific calibre that the workplace calls for. More importantly, some college students prepare for these examinations at the cost of their major disciplines, which could do more harm than good to their careers in long terms and defeat the purpose of certificate-gaining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For another, learning is an end in itself. It is those confounding moments, self-discovery after self-doubt that make knowledge so desirable. A healthy way of learning inculcates in students a love for the subject, not just what the test requires, so the students can, and most importantly will, make the subject their business to learn. Most students, on the other hand, are swamped by exam-oriented education, deprived of the joy of mental adventure, so that creativity and ingenuous pursuit of knowledge can never be attained. While they are preparing for the examination related to certificates, reference books, didactic teaching, rote learning and cramming schooling play a major role. They are told so, and without serious consideration, another quiz begins. This process, however, produces only dilettantes with a smattering of knowledge that would soon grow unlearned. Of greater concern is that they may become unable to explore a new field without an all-knowing guide, but there is rarely a guide in practical working experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By no means am I making the conclusion that certificates are pure evil, for they can be equally used for good. Certificates and examinations correlated to one’s interests and consistent with his / her professional aspirations can, in most cases, cultivate one’s ability and guide them through the job market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On balance, I believe that certificates do little to enhance one’s capability until we have poured in meaning efforts in something that would give meaning help in the days to come. Certificates itself is neutral, and we could use it to our advantage once we follow an appropriate way to learn. We should always acquire knowledge from the process and keep exploring and thinking instead of be guided by utilitarianism. Only in this way can we truly improve our abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
