<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors | Qiushi Yan</title>
    <link>https://qiushi.rbind.io/authors/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://qiushi.rbind.io/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Authors</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Qiushi Yan © 2021</copyright>
    <image>
      <url>https://qiushi.rbind.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Authors</title>
      <link>https://qiushi.rbind.io/authors/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://qiushi.rbind.io/authors/qiushi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qiushi.rbind.io/authors/qiushi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately I have been applying to master programs in Data Science and Statistics. If you find this site, you probably want to know more about me and why I am a promising candidate through the following links. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://qiushi.rbind.io/about&#34;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt; page is a complement to my personal statement, elaborating on my passion for data science and background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://qiushi.rbind.io/files/titanic-survival.pdf&#34;&gt;Modeling Titanic Survival&lt;/a&gt;: A 30-page case study on the most up-to-date and comprehensive Titanic survival data. A binary logistic model is built to analyze survival probability given characteristics such as age, gender, cabin class, nationality, embarkation point, etc. I demonstrate the overall modeling process, including preprocessing, exploratory analysis,  model fitting, adjustment, bootstrap internal validation and interpretation as well as other relevant techniques such as redundancy analysis and multiple imputation for missing data. The article also touches on key issues such as the choice of a statistical model or a machine learning model, using bootstrap to alleviate selection bias, disadvantages of the holdout sample approach in validation, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&#34;https://enixam.github.io/math-foundations/&#34;&gt;Mathematical Notes for Data Science and Statistics&lt;/a&gt;: in-progress notes in Linear Algebra, Multivariate Calculus, Optimization and Probability Theory&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;post/text-classification-logistic/&#34;&gt;Classify Brontë Sisters with Penalized Logistic Regression&lt;/a&gt;: I trained a logistic model with lasso penalty to predict the probability of a line being authored by Emily Brontë or Charlotte Brontë, featuring text processing, cross validation and grid search, and interpretation based on variable importance plots. A later &lt;a href=&#34;post/2020-05-07-analyzing-animal-crossing-reviews&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; extended this idea to build a multinomial regressor classifying customer reviews into 3 categories, taking advantage of upsampling to counteract class imbalance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal R package &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/enixam/ymisc&#34;&gt;ymisc&lt;/a&gt;. This is my first attempt at developing an R package, which currently contains miscellaneous functions for general hypothesis testing in multiple linear regression, converting multiple file encodings, writing a grouped by data frame to separate files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;post/python-tidy-data/&#34;&gt;Tidy Data with Python&lt;/a&gt;: a blog post on tidying messing data in Hadley Wickham’s Tidy Data paper, using python&amp;rsquo;s pandas library&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://qiushi.rbind.io/post/analyzing-covid-19-publications/&#34;&gt;Analyzing COVID-19 Publications&lt;/a&gt;:  Text analysis on the abstract of publications on the coronavirus disease (COVID-19). Use weighted log odds and LDA topic model for information extraction. Finish with a network visualization of word correlation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &amp;ldquo;My Life In Months&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://qiushi.rbind.io/img/life_in_months.png&#34;&gt;plot&lt;/a&gt; illustrating my relevant experience in the field&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://enixam.github.io/fpp/&#34;&gt;Time Series Analysis with R&lt;/a&gt;: Another notes in time series analysis using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://tidyverts.org/&#34;&gt;tidyverts&lt;/a&gt; framework&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/enixam&#34;&gt;Github profile&lt;/a&gt;: I have been active in coding and contributing to open source projects ever since I decide to pursue such a career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://qiushi.rbind.io/post&#34;&gt;More Posts&lt;/a&gt;: a list of all my other projects in data analysis and machine learning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am currently a fourth-year student majoring in data journalism at &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.cuc.edu.cn/&#34;&gt;Communication University of China&lt;/a&gt;. I enjoy applied statistics as well as &amp;ldquo;modern&amp;rdquo; data science initiatives. I take particular interest in data wrangling, visualizing and modeling in &lt;code&gt;#rstats&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to data stuff, I take delight in Chinese Literature, nature &amp;amp; ecology documentaries, and cat videos. My favorite author is Bertrand Russell ✒.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
